The John Carter Glenn Collection
Yale University Music Library
The John Carter Glenn Collection
1886-1912
MSS 9
Yale University Music Library
0.25
(1 box)
Autographs and letters of musicians collected by John Carter Glenn
Glenn, John Carter
Conditions Governing Access
The Collection is open to researchers by appointment. There are no restricted materials in the collection. Please contact the Special Collections staff to schedule an appointment.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically.
Scope and Contents
The John Carter Glenn Collection consists primarily of cards autographed by composers, musical performers, and instrument makers. The Collection also holds 4 autograph letters: 1 letter from Georg Gemünder to Jesse Weissman, and 1 letter each from Victor Herbert, Moritz Moszkowski, and Anton Seidl, all to Albert Weissman.
Autographs -- Collections; Composers -- Autographs; Musicians -- Autographs; Violin makers -- Autographs; Albert, Eugen d', 1864-1932; Burke, Billie, 1885-1970; Campanini, Italo, 1845-1896; Fischer, Emil, 1838-1914; Friedheim, Arthur, 1859-1932; Gemünder, George, 1816-1899; Grünfeld, Alfred, 1852-1924; Grünfeld, Heinrich, 1855-1931; Hegner, Otto, 1876-1907; Herbert, Victor, 1859-1924; Joseffy, Rafael, 1852-1915; Lambert, Alexander, 1862-1929; Moszkowski, Moritz, 1854-1925; Pachmann, Vladimir de, 1848-1933; Paderewski, Ignace Jan, 1860-1941; Pizzi, Emilio; Rosenthal, Moriz, 1862-1946; Sarasate, Pablo de, 1844-1908; Scharwenka, Xaver, 1850-1924; Seidl, Anton, 1850-1898; Tchaikovsky, Peter Ilich, 1840-1893; Van der Stucken, Frank V., 1858-1929
- Autographs and Letters
  - d'Albert, Eugen, no date; autograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Brandt, M[arianne]?, no date; autograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Bülow, Joseph, 1890 May 7; autograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Burke, Billie, 1912 Dec 3; autographed program (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Campanini, Italo, 1891 Apr 14; autograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Fischer, Emil, no date; autograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Friedheim, Arthur, no date; autograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Gemünder, George to Jesse Weissman, 1890 Dec 30; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Grünfeld, Alfred, no date; autograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Grünfeld, Heinrich, no date; autograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Hegner, Otto, 1889 Feb 11; autograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Herbert, Victor to Albert Weissman, 1891 Dec 16; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Joseffy, Rafael, 1890 Sep.; autograph (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Lambert, Alexander, 1887 Mar 8; autograph (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Moszkowski, Moritz to Albert Weissman, 1886 Feb 12; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Pachmann, Vladimir de, 1891 Dec 16; autograph (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Paderewski, Ignace Jan, no date; autograph (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Patti, Adelina, 1886 Nov 15; autograph (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Pizzi, Emilio, no date; autograph (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Rosenthal, Moriz, no date; autograph (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Sarasate, Pablo de, 1890 May 17; autograph (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Scharwenka, Xaver, 1890 Jul 29; autograph (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Seidl, Anton to Albert Weissman, 1888 Apr 8; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Tchaikovsky, Peter Ilich, 1891 May 8; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Van der Stucken, Frank, 1886 Nov 9; autograph (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - unidentified, no date; 2 autographs (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - for perfume company, 1900 (Paris); advertisement (Box 1, Folder 2)
    General
    written in Russian